Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Theatre Programs, 1840-present CTC.1966.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- 19th Century Pittsburgh Theatres, 1840-1935; I.; 2 boxes
  - Pittsburgh Opera House, 1871-1916; 10.
    - Pittsburgh Opera House
      - Broadside - Hess' Grand English Opera Company in The Chimes of Normandy; Bohemian Girl; Martha; Villars' Dragoons, March 4, 1978; 45.
      - Opera program - Hess' Grand English Opera Company in The Chimes of Normandy, March 4, 1978; 46.
      - Theatre program - Othello with Edwin Booth, April 13, 1878; 47.
      - Theatre program - The Danites with McKee Rankin and Kitty Blanchard, September 21, 1878; 48.
      - Theatre program - Little Em'ly with George Fawcett Rowe, January 23, 1879; 49.
      - Theatre program - Ingomar with Mary Anderson and John W. Norton, February 8, 1879; 50.
      - Theatre program - H. M. S. Pinafore with Effie Ellsler, March 15, 1879; 51.
      - Opera program - Huguenots with Clara Kellogg, March 31, 1879; 52.
      - Opera program - Evangeline!, May 3, 1879; 53.
      - Theatre program - Fanchon with Maggie Mitchell and William Harris, September 21, 1879; 54.
      - Burlesque program - Emerson's Megatherian Minstrels in Schoolcraft's Visit; Frank Naoni; Harry Robinson; etc., October 25, 1879; 55.
      - Theatre program - Sarah's Young Man! and Comedy of Errors with Stuart Robson and William H. Crane, November 8, 1879; 56.
      - Burlesque program - Haverly's United Mastodon Minstrels in Pea-Tea Bar-None's; Sam Devere; Harry Kennedy; etc., November 25, 1879; 57.
      - Theatre program - Zip or, Point Lynde Light with Lotta Crabtree, January 29, 1880; 58.
      - Burlesque program - Colville Opera Burlesque Co. in Il Trovatore, or, The Mother, The Maiden, and The Musicianer, April 20, 1880; 59.
      - Theatre program - Sharps and Flats with Stuart Robson and William H. Crane, October 23, 1880; 60.
      - Theatre program - Herrmann the Great performance, January 3, 1881; 61.
      - Opera program - H.B. Mahn's English Comic Opera Company in Boccaccio, January 15, 1881; 68.
      - Theatre program - The Rivals with Joseph Jefferson, February 21, 1881; 69.
      - Theatre program - Rip Van Winkle with Joseph Jefferson, February 21, 1881; 70.
      - Vaudeville program - Ingomar; The Rough Diamond; J. A. Hoffman; and the Baer Brothers benefit performance for Harry Ellsler, June 9, 1881; 71.
      - Opera program - The Emma Abbott Grand Opera Company in Olivette, November 24, 1881; 72.
      - Theatre program - The World, October 2, 1882; 73.
      - Burlesque program - Haverly's Mastodon Minstrels performing The Old Kentucky Home! and Her Majesty's Opera!, October 9, 1882; 74.
      - Theatre program - The White Slave!, February 5, 1883; 75.
      - Opera program - The C.D. Hess Acme English Opera Co. in The Mascotte!, March 3, 1883; 76.
      - Opera program - The C.D. Hess Acme English Opera Co. in Fra Diavolo!, March 3, 1883; 77.
      - Theatre program - Frou-Frou! with Helena Modjeska, March 9, 1883; 78.
      - Opera program - Mardi-Gras! with Marie Geistinger, April 17, 1883; 79.
      - Opera program - The Bat; or 14 Days with Marie Geistinger, April 19, 1883; 80.
      - Opera program - Three Pair of Shoes with Marie Geistinger, April 20, 1883; 81.
      - Opera program - Boccaccio; or, The Prince of Palermo with Marie Geistinger, April 21, 1883; 82.
      - Theatre program - Jane Eyre with Maggie Mitchell, December 24, 1883; 83.
      - Theatre program - Princess Ida! or, Castle Adamant, April 14, 1884; 84.
      - Theatre program - The Bandit King with James. H. Wallick, September 28, 1885; 85.
      - Theatre program - Anselma with Madame Janish, October 19, 1885; 86.
      - Theatre program - Comedy of Errors with Stuart Robson and William H. Crane, April 5, 1886; 87.
      - Theatre program - The Merry Wives of Windsor with Stuart Robson and William H. Crane, September 27, 1886; 88.
      - Theatre Program - Meg Merrilies with Francesca Janauschek, January 17, 1887; 89.
      - Opera program - The Conried English Opera Company in The Gypsy Baron with Laura Bellini, February 21, 1887; 90.
      - Opera program - The Temple Theater Comic Opera Company in The Little Tycoon, March 28, 1887; 91.
      - Opera program - The Boston Ideal Opera Company in Musketeers, April 18, 1887; 92.
    - Grand Opera House, 1887-1899
      - Theatre program - Brutus or The Fall of Tarquin! with Frederick Warde, October 3, 1887; 1.
      - Theatre program - Galba, The Gladiator with Frederick Warde, October 3, 1887; 2.
      - Theatre program - Richard III with Frederick Warde, October 4, 1887; 3.
      - Theatre program - Lost in the Snow, October 10, 1887; 4.
      - Theatre program - A Parlor Match with Charles E. Evans and William Hoey, October 24, 1887; 5.
      - Theatre program - Julius Caesar with Edwin Booth and Lawrence Barrett, November 21, 1887; 6.
      - Theatre program - Lagardere, December 12, 1887; 7.
      - Advertising - The Deacon's Daughter; The Charity Girl; and M'Liss with Annie Pixley, January 2, 1888; 8.
      - Theatre program - Othello with Edwin Booth and Lawrence Barrett, January 7, 1888; 9.
      - Theatre program - French and Sanger's Company in Harbor Lights, February 13, 1888; 10.
      - Opera program - Conried English Opera Company in The Vice Admiral, May 7, 1888; 11.
      - Theatre program - A Midnight Bell, November 12, 1889; 12.
      - Theatre program - The Henrietta with Stuart Robson and William H. Crane *Oversized?*, March 11, 1889; 13.
      - Opera program - Carmen; Il Trovatore; The Bohemian Girl; Postilion of Lonjumeau; Faust; Mignon; Maritana; and The Freischutz with Emma Juch, December 23, 1889; 14.
      - Theatre program - Virginius with Frederick Warde and Elizabeth Crocker Bowers, November 17, 1890; 15.
      - Opera program - Carmen with Emma Juch, November 16, 1891; 16.
      - Theatre program - Romeo and Juliet with Julia Marlowe, May 23, 1892; 17.
      - Vaudeville program - Nita's First; Rossow Midgets; Carr & McLeod; Mlle. Chalet; Tom Mack, January 24, 1898; 18.
      - Vaudeville program - Jane; Sager and Fanny Midgley; Pete Baker; Hadj Lessik, February 6, 1899; 19.
      - Vaudeville program - A Parisian Romance; Billy Van; Prof. Morris' Trained Ponies, April 10, 1899; 20.
  - Pittsburg Theatre, 1867
  - Old City Hall, 1892; 11.
    - Theatre program - Bill Nye and A. P. Burbank, April 9, 1892; 1.
  - Seventeenth Ward Public School Hall, 1871-1875
    - Theatre program - Les Miserables; The Intelligence Office; Local Troubles, or the Deputy's Morning Court, November 28, 1872; 1.
    - Theatre program - The Idiot Witness; The Boston Jubilee, and To Paris and Back For Five Pounds!, March 5, 1875; 2.
  - Shakespeare Reading Club, 1879
    - Theatre program - Much Ado About Nothing at the house of Mr. William Thaw, January 17, 1879; 1.
  - Tivoli Garden, 1886
  - Trimble's Varieties Theatre, 1875-1876
    - Vaudeville program - Kernell & Thatchers Minstrels!; Rip Van Winkle or, The Sleep of Twenty Years with Billy DeVere; etc, 1.
    - Vaudeville program - Miss Ettie Romaine; Squire for a Day; etc., December 1875; 2.
    - Vaudeville program - The Grand Conservatory Female Serenaders!; The Great Classical Living Statue Troupe; Live Indian!; etc, January 7, 1876; 3.
- 20th Century Pittsburgh Theatres, 1901-current; II.
  - Allegheny Repertory Theatre, 1980-1984; 1.; 1 box
  - American Ibsen Theatre, 1983-1988; 2.; 1 box
  - Apple Hill Playhouse, 1964-2001; 3.; 1 box
    Also contains materials relating to Johnny Apple Seed's Children's Theatre and Orchard Performing Arts Company.
  - Art Cinema, 4.; 1 box
    The Art Cinema was purchased by The Pittsburgh Cultural Trust and renamed the Harris Theater. It has been programmed and operated by Pittsburgh Filmmakers since 1995. Materials relating to both names are filed under Art Cinema.
  - August Wilson Center for African American Culture, 2003-current; 5.; 1 box
    Programs from the August Wilson Center are filed in the Pittsburgh Cultural District subseries.
  - Avenue Cinema, 1931-1940; 6.; 1 box
  - Benedum Center for Performing Arts, 1985-1999; 7.; 8 boxes
    Programs dated after December 1999 are filed with the Pittsburgh Cultural District boxes.
    - Theatre program - Grand opening of the Benedum Center Purely Pittsburgh, Pilobolus Dance Theatre, Rosemary Clooney, Lionel Hampton, and George Benson with Nathan Davis and the Pittsburgh Jazz Orchestra, September 25, 1987; 1.
  - Bricolage Production Company, 2004-current; 8.; 1 box
  - Brockett Productions, 1984-1999; 9.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Don Brockett and Barbara Russell in Last Polka in Pittsburgh, 1.
    - Theatre program - Forbidden Pittsburgh, May 2, 1985; 2.
  - Byham Theater, 1995-1999; 10.; 1 box
    Previously the Fulton Theater. Programs dated after December 1999 are filed with the Pittsburgh Cultural District boxes.
  - Camelot Productions, 1974-1978; 11.; 1 box
  - Carnegie Mellon University, 1915-current; 12.; 7 boxes
  - Carnegie Music Hall, 1901-current; 13.; 1 box
    - Concert program - Pittsburgh Orchestra performance, November 29, 1901; 1.
    - Concert program - Ignacy Jan Paderewski performance, March 10, 1902; 2.
  - Center Stage Dinner Theatre, 1980-1984; 14.; 1 box
  - Characters East Theatre, 1977-1983; 15.; 1 box
  - Chatham College, 1932-current; 16.; 3 boxes
  - Christian Arts Company/Saltworks, 1981-1999; 17.; 1 box
  - City Players, 1975-1981; 18.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Death and Life of Sneaky Fitch first production by the City Players, June 19, 1975; 1.
  - City Theatre Company, 1981-current; 19.; 6 boxes
    - Theatre program - Bricklayers first production at the South Side City Theatre, November 30, 1991; 1.
    - Theatre program - A Raisin in the Sun co-produced by City Theatre and Kuntu Repertory Theatre, September 10, 1999; 2.
  - Civic Light Opera, 1946-current; 20.; 15 boxes
    - Theatre program - Naughty Marietta the Civic Light Opera's first production, June 1, 1946; 1.
    - Theatre program - Carol Burnett Show first production at the Civic Arena, July 2, 1962; 2.
    - Souvenir theatre program - Carol Burnett Show premiere performance at the Civic Arena, July 2, 1962; 3.
    - Theatre program - Kinky Boots with Billy Porter, August 4, 2015; 4.
  - Churches, 1938-current; 21.; 1 box
    All productions staged at a church or other religous center are filed here.
  - Community College of Allegheny County, 1979-1995; 22.; 1 box
  - Comtra Theater, 1981-1989; 23.; 1 box
  - Cresson Lake Playhouse, 1974-1987; 24.; 1 box
  - Davis Theatre, 1915-1929; 25.; 1 box
    The Davis Theatre was a part of the B. F. Keith Vaudeville Circuit.
    - Vaudeville program - Houdini Chinese Water Torture Cell performance, November 6, 1916; 1.
    - Vaudeville program - Houdini performance, February 23, 1925; 2.
  - Duquesne Garden, 1927-1937; 26.; 1 box
  - Duquesne University, 1928-current; 27.; 1 box
  - East End Theatre, 1926-1928; 28.; 1 box
  - Enright Theatre, 29.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Screening of Adoration inaugural performance at the Enright, December 28, 1928; 1.
  - Famous Rider, 1983-1986; 30.; 1 box
  - Fine Line Theatre Company, 1977-1983; 31.; 1 box
  - Fulton Theater, 1989-1996; 32.; 1 box
    Renamed the Byham Theater in 1995. Previously known as the Gayety Theatre.
    - Theatre program - Reopening of the Fulton Give 'Em Hell Harry, May 31, 1991; 1.
  - Gayety Theatre, 1904-1928; 33.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Way Down East first production at the Gayety, October 31, 1904; 1.
  - Gemini Theatre Company, 1997-current; 34.; 1 box
  - Glenshaw Players, 1955-1979; 35.; 1 box
  - Greensburg Civic Theatre, 1976-current; 36.; 1 box
  - Hartwood Theatre on the Green, 1980-1996; 37.; 1 box
  - Hazlett Theater, 2004-current; 38.; 1 box
  - Heinz Hall, 1971-1999; 39.; 19 boxes
    - Concert program - Inaugural Concert at Heinz Hall by the Pittsburgh Symphony Orechestra, September 11, 1971; 1.
    - Opera program - Pittsburgh Opera Aida, October 7, 1971; 2.
  - Hippodrome, 1909-1927; 40.; 1 box
  - Indiana University of Pennyslvania, 1966-2007; 41.; 2 boxes
  - International Poetry Forum, 1974-1991; 42.; 1 box
  - Iron Clad Agreement, 1976-1981; 43.; 1 box
  - Jewish Community Center, 1975-2006; 44.; 1 box
  - Kuntu Repertory Theatre, 1975-2013; 45.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Little Willie Armstrong Jones Kuntu's inaugural production, April 15, 1975; 1.
  - Laurel Highlands Regional Theatre, 1985-1992; 46.; 1 box
  - Little Lake, 1949-current; 47.; 2 boxes
  - Loew's Aldine, 1925-1926
  - Mckeesport Little Theater, 1974-2001; 48.; 1 box
  - Mountain Playhouse, 1940-current; 49.; 4 boxes
  - 99¢ Floating Theater, 1974-1981; 50.; 1 box
  - New Group Theater, 1982-1999; 51.; 1 box
  - New Horizons, 1993-current; 52.; 1 box
  - New Works Festival, 1991-current; 53.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - New Works Festival, October 17, 1991; 1.
  - Nixon Theatre, 1903-1976; 54.; 19 boxes
    - Theatre program - Erminie inaugual performance at the Nixon, December 7, 1903; 1.
    - Theatre program - The Prince of Pilsen, January 4, 1904; 2.
      Please note that this program has an incorrect date. The production began on January 4th, 1904.
    - Theatre program - Three Little Maids, Februaury 1, 1904; 3.
    - Theatre program - The Wizard of Oz, Februaury 22, 1904; 4.
    - Theatre program - The Darling of the Gods with Blanche Bates, April 18, 1904; 5.
    - Theatre program - The Yankee Consul with Raymond Hitchcock, September 12, 1904; 6.
    - Theatre program - Little Minister with Maude Adams, November 14, 1904; 7.
    - Theatre program - The Usurper with N.C. Goodwin, November 21, 1904; 8.
    - Theatre program - The Taming of the Shrew and The School for Scandal with Ada Rehan and Charles Richman, December 19, 1904; 9.
    - Theatre program - Lillian Russell Opera Company in Lady Teazle, May 22, 1905; 10.
    - Theatre program - Little Johnny Jones with George M. Cohan, September 11, 1905; 11.
    - Advertising - The Wizard of Oz, December 1905; 12.
    - Theatre program - The College Widow, January 8, 1906; 13.
    - Theatre program - The Catch of the Season with Edna May, Febraury 12, 1906; 14.
    - Theatre program - The Toast of the Town with Viola Allen a benefit performance for the Pittsburgh and Alleheny Free Kindergarten Association, March 14, 1906; 15.
    - Theatre program - Actor's Fund of America benefit, April 19, 1910; 16.
    - Theatre program - Diamond Lil with Mae West the final production at the Nixon, April 24, 1950; 17.
  - Odd Chair Playhouse, 1968-1975; 55.; 1 box
  - Open Stage Theatre, 1992-current; 56.; 1 box
  - Opera Theater of Pittsburgh, 1985-current; 57.; 1 box
  - Park Players, 1971-1980; 58.; 1 box
  - Penn Theatre, 1963-1967; 59.; 1 box
  - Performing Arts for Children Series, 1970-current; 60.; 1 box
  - Pershing Theatre, 1920
  - Pitt Theatre, 1920-1932; 61.; 2 boxes
    - Advertising - Isadora Duncan performance, October 1916; 1.
    - Film program - Intolerance, December 22, 1916; 2.
    - Film program supplement - Facts Worth Knowing for Intolerance, December 22, 1916; 3.
    - Film program supplement - A Declaration of Personal Independence, Away with Meddlers for Intolerance, December 22, 1916; 4.
    - Theatre program - E.H. Sothern and Julia Marlowe in Shakespeare's Plays, March 15, 1920; 5.
    - Theatre program - The Bat based on the novel by Mary Roberts Rinehart, September 25, 1922; 6.
    - Film program - Robin Hood with Douglas Fairbanks, January 15, 1923; 7.
  - Pittsburgh Area Dinner Theatre, 1974-2004; 1 box
  - Pittsburgh Cultural District, 2000-current; 62.; 11 boxes
    Contains all programs dated after December of 1999 for the August Wilson Center, Benedum Center, Heinz Hall, and the Byham Theater.
    - Theatre program - Off the Record, October 10, 2001; 1.
    - Theatre program - The Aunt Ester Cycle with The St. Louis Black Rep in Gem of the Ocean; Pittsburgh Playwrights Theatre Company in Two Trains Running; Penumbra Theatre Company in Raido Golf, November 2009; 2.
  - Pittsburgh Drama League, 1914-1981; 63.; 2 boxes
  - Pittsburgh High School for the Creative and Performing Arts, 1990-current; 64.; 1 box
  - Pittsburgh Irish & Classical Theatre, 1997-current; 65.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - The Constant Couple, June 1997; 1.
  - Pittsburgh Laboratory Theatre, 1971-1984; 66.; 5 boxes
  - Pittsburgh Metropolitan Stage Company, 1979-1985; 67.; 1 box
  - Pittsburgh Musical Theater, 1990-2003; 68.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat, December 5, 1990; 1.
  - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1995-current; 69.; 5 boxes
    Programs dated before 1995 are filed with the Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater Records.
  - Pittsburgh Playwrights Theatre, 70.
    - Theatre program - Boppin' with the Ancestors, June 2003; 1.
    - Theatre program - Theater Festival in Black & White, October 14, 2003; 2.
    - Theatre program - Seven Guitars, August 2016; 3.
  - Pittsburgh Poor Players, 1973-1974; 71.; 1 box
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1975-current; 72.; 16 boxes
    - Theatre program - Inaugural Pittsburgh Public Theater production The Glass Menagerie, September 17, 1975; 1.
    - Theatre program - One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest with Tom Atkins, October 22, 1975; 2.
    - Theatre program - Twelfth Night with Leonard Nimoy, November 26, 1975; 3.
    - Theatre program - Joe Turner's Come and Gone with August Wilson autograph, September 7, 1989; 4.
    - Theatre program - Inaugural performance at the O'Reilly Theater King Hedley II world premiere, December 11, 1999; 5.
    - Theatre program - The Chief world premiere, November 6, 2003; 6.
  - Pittsburgh Savoyards, 1975-current; 73.; 2 boxes
  - Prime Stage, 1996-current; 74.; 1 box
  - Quantum Theatre, 2001-current; 75.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Pedro Páramo, April 1991; 1.
    - Theatre program - Someone Who'll Watch Over Me, April 1994; 2.
  - Red Barn Theatre, 1973-2001; 76.; 1 box
  - Robert Morris College, 1968-1992; 77.; 2 boxes
  - St. Vincent's College, 1979-1996; 78.; 1 box
  - Schenley Theatre, 1914-1940; 79.; 1 box
  - Scope and Scalpel Society, 1965-1979; 80.; 1 box
  - Sherwood Forest Theatre, 1959-1994; 81.; 1 box
  - South Park Conservatory Theatre, 1977-1979; 82.; 1 box
  - Soho Repertory Theatre, 1979-1982; 83.; 1 box
  - Stanley Theatre, 1928-1984; 84.; 2 boxes
    - Program - Inaugural orchestral performance of Capriccio Italien and screening of Gentlemen Prefer Blondes, February 27, 1928; 1.
  - Strand-Rialto Theatres, 1916-1920
  - Syria Mosque, 1929-1991; 85.; 2 boxes
    - Theatre program - Original Freiburg Passion Play, November 17, 1930; 1.
    - Dance program - Mamie W. Barth School of the Dance annual exhibition, April 28th, 1931; 2.
    - Concert program - Marian Anderson recital, March 20, 1942; 3.
    - Opera program - Pittsburgh Opera in Manon, November 20, 1952; 4.
    - Advertising - Rock 'n Roll show featuring Bill Haley and his Comets, May 3, 1956; 5.
  - Theatre Express, 1977-1981; 86.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Endgame, February 14, 1980
  - Theatre Factory, 1999-2010; 87.; 1 box
  - Unseam'd Shakespeare Company, 1994-current; 88.; 1 box
  - Upstairs Theatre, 1988-1995; 89.; 1 box
  - Valley Players of Ligonier, 1982-current; 90.; 1 box
  - Veronica's Veil Players, 1926-current; 91.; 1 box
  - White Barn Theatre, 1948-1984; 92.; 2 boxes
  - Wilkinsburg Arts Theatre, 1987-1993; 93.; 1 box
    - Theatre program - Ceremonies in Dark Old Men, March 31, 1989; 1.
    - Theatre program - Black Nativity, November 30, 1989; 2.
  - William Penn Playhouse, 1952-1959; 94.; 1 box
- Oversized programs, III.; 1 box